Shubham Gulati

Senior Software Engineer • Certified Cloud Architect • 7 Years Experience • B.Tech & M.Tech Waterloo, ON • linkedin.com/in/iamshqulati • shubhamqulati.com

PROFILE

Shubham is an award-winning Senior Software Engineer with 7 years of exceptional IT experience at industry leading U.S. and Canadian professional services firms. He has a Masters degree in Computer Science & Engineering and is certified in AWS. His core competencies include cloud-native web application development using Java, Spring Boot, and Microservices.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Technology Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2022-2022

- ◆ Lead a team of junior developers that enhanced the accuracy of a reporting application by 30%.
- Streamlined development lifecycle by enforcing coding best practices and improved reliability of the system.
- Reduced the risk of security incidents by designing a framework to fetch configuration secrets from HashiCorp Vault.

Technology Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2019-2022

- Developed the client's support portal which is a one stop shop for all the support related needs for business users.
- Reduced technical debt for a major client project by developing a common foundation for microservice modules.
- Improved the performance of mission-critical features by 25% by optimizing code and database queries.

Technology Analyst, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2018-2019

- Developed client's HR Portal which was a regulated product with highly sensitive data and numerical operations.
- Reduced the operational costs of the portal by 20% by re-writing Coldfusion application using Java & Spring Boot.
- Improved the efficiency and security of the modules by 80% by re-architecting backend services for the cloud.

Associate Software Engineer, CGI Inc

India - 2016-2018

- Developed a framework to manage the state of system which reduced the maintenance downtime by 95%.
- ◆ Migrated SOAP web services to REST endpoints using modern Spring Boot-based microservices.

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Certificate, Computer Application Security, Conestoga CollegeWaterloo, ONPostgraduate Certificate, Cloud Computing & Blockchain, Saskatchewan PolytechnicSaskatoon, SKMaster of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information TechnologyIndiaBachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information TechnologyIndia

CERTIFICATIONS

CompTIA Security+, CompTIAPursuingAWS Certified Developer Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)PursuingAWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)FPDELC1KXFF1QXK5

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

JJMV6422RJ1Q1NWV

SKILLS

Backend – Java, Microservices, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, JPA, Hibernate, REST, GraphQL, Git, SQL, OpenAPI, Swagger

Infra / Cloud – AWS (EC2, S3, DynamoDB, CloudFormation, IAM), GCP, GitHub Actions, Docker, Jenkins

Security – pfSense, GVM, Nessus, Cryptography, PKI, Risk Assessment, Threat Modelling, Ghidra, IDA, Reconnaissance

Frontend – SSG, SSR, Typescript, React, HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, Next.js, Astro.js

August 24, 2024 Shubham Gulati • Résumé 1 of 2

AWARDS

Conestoga	- High Distinction Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Computer Application Security.	2024
Conestoga	- Best of Program Award, Best Capstone Project in Computer Application Security program.	2024
Saskpoly	– Dean's List Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Cloud Computing & Blockchain.	2023
Deloitte	 Applause Award, Technical contribution to the success of the eCX project. 	2022
Deloitte	- Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the STAR Migration project.	2020
Deloitte	 Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the HRAlly project. 	2019
Deloitte	- Applause Award, Project delivery excellence during the development of the HRAlly project.	2019
Deloitte	 Spot Award, Critical support during CSP 2.0 project go-live. 	2019
Deloitte	 Applause Award, Delivery excellence during CSP 2.0 project development. 	2018
CGI	- Apex Award, Unsupervised delivery, and individual contribution to the M2M GDSP project.	2017

PROJECTS

Blog	_	Self-taught React, Typescript, TailwindCSS, Next.js, and Astro.js to build a blog with a simple design.
OSCAR	-	Secured Maven build supply chain for OSCAR, an open-source Canadian Healthcare EMR system.
Emoverse	-	Built a full-stack journaling platform using AWS serverless services, and fully automated CI-CD pipeline.
SmartDegree	_	Built a DApp to issue digital certificates using Solidity and Web3 and deployed on Ethereum blockchain.
DevMyMacX	_	Self-taught shell scripting to automate user and developer environment setup on a fresh macOS install.
DevMyLinuX	_	Self-taught shell scripting to automate Arch Linux OS and environment setup with minimal user interaction.

PUBLICATIONS

Research Paper

- An efficient technique to control road traffic using Fuzzy Neural Network System.
- Published in the IEEE Journal https://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICRITO.2014.7014723